Carey Orr Cartoons
Carey Orr Cartoons
- Cartoons
  - 1916-1928
    - Those White House pets., 1927; 1927.0147.Orr; Pres. Coolidge" sits at a desk writing when a camel labeled "Prohibition Enforcement" sticks its head through a window and disrupts him. Surrounding his desk are crates labeled to him at the White House with a menagerie of animals. The animals are labeled "China,"Chinese trouble."Nicaragua,"Gov.'t waste,"Mexican troubles,"England's pet peeve,"Debt howl," and "Debt cancelationist." Coolidge says, "I wish folks wouldn't send me so many pets!" Outside a delivery man carries another package and says, "Package for Mr. Coolidge."and Grace Coolidge had several breeds of dogs, birds, cats, racoons, a donkey, bobcat and animals given to them by dignitaries from other countries including lion cubs, a wallaby, pigmy hippo and a bear. Portion of preliminary sketch for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Touching our heart strings., 1927; 1927.0148.Orr; Santa Claus is labeled the "Spirit of Christmas" and he is sitting playing a harp in the shape of a heart. The harp is labeled "Sympathy for the unfortunate." He says, "It's still in tune." The music is labeled "Charity,"Kindliness," and "Good fellowship." cols Monday am" written on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by, The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Turning the animals loose., 1927; 1927.0149.Orr; An ark labeled "U.S.Ark" has landed on ground labeled "The present era." On board is a man labeled "Politics" that is suppose to represent Noah}. A man labeled "Public" says to him, "Say, Noah, what was the idea in bringin' all this menagerie along?" Exiting the ark are a camel labeled "National Prohibition," a snake labeled "Political crookedness," a chimp labeled "Tennessee anti-evolution trial," a wolf wearing a lambs coat labeled "Indiana K.K.K's," a lion labeled "Chicago's pro-British bunk, and an ostrich labeled "Wisconsin pacifism."overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Two birds with one shot., 1927; 1927.0150.Orr; A man labeled "Voter" is standing at a fence with his gun labeled "Moderation." The smoke from the fired gun forms the words "November election." In the foreground are two dead birds labeled "Extreme wets of Detroit" and "Extreme drys of Ohio" that are lying on the ground debt. The "Voter" points to all the gunshot holes in the fence and says "I aimed in between'em!"sketches for unknown cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - The ultimate price of pacifism., 1927; 1927.0151.Orr; A man in the left corner is labeled "Our generation". He holds a paper that is labeled "Failure to protect America." Scattered around his feet are papers that read, "Peace at any price,"Neglect of our Navy,"Altruism,"Neglect of our Army," and "Pacifism." In the upper right corner is a man lying on the ground labeled "Future Generations with his fist in the air to "Our Generation." On his back is the foot of a man in military uniform labeled "The heel of the conqueror."sketches for unknown cartoon on verso. "3 cols am" written on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - The take off., 31 May 1927; 1927.0152.Orr; A "June graduate" is waving goodbye as he sits in a plane labeled "June'27,"Knowledge," and "Book learnin.'" He is taking off from the "Campus Field" to "Fame and Fortune" ahead in the "Outside World." In the foreground is a piece of paper labeled "Weather Report. - Rain, hail, snow, sleet and icebergs." cols Tuesday am, May 31." written on recto bottom edge. Torn paper overlay: The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - That's my boy!", 1927; 1927.0153.Orr; Uncle Sam is standing on the shores of the U.S. with his vest buttons popping with pride. The crowds of people are cheering "Hoo-ray for Lindbergh!" A small kitten says, "Three purrs for Lindbergh's kitten!" In the far distance is the Eiffel Tower and the text "Vive Lindbergh! He made it!"Lindbergh arrived in Parish on May 27, 1926 after completing the first non-stop flight between New York and Paris. The flight was 3,600 miles long and took 33.5 hours. - Not sure why this cartoon has a 1927 date on it. Preliminary sketches for unknown cartoon on verso. "3 cols Monday am" written on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - They've got to quit tying cans to our Towser's tail., 1927; 1927.0154.Orr; A bandaged up dog labeled "U.S." and "Timid foreign policy" has a tail labeled "Foreign interests" with cans tied to his tail. The cans are labeled "Trouble with China,"Trouble with Nicaragua," and "Trouble with Mexico." A boy labeled "Indignant American" has his hands on the dog's muzzle and says, "Let's take his muzzle off!" Another boy labeled "Our Pacifists" puts up his hand and says, "O Mercy, No! He might bite somebody - Let's cut his tail off!" To the right is a tree stump with an axe wedged in it. The axe is labeled "Refusal to protect U.S. Citizens abroad."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - To the woodshed, again.", 1927; 1927.0155.Orr; A man labeled "Landis" has a switch in one hand and is taking a young boy labeled "Baseball" behind a gate labeled "Baseball Investigation." In the background is a window broken in a house. The window is labeled "Public confidence." A baseball glove is on the ground and labeled "Crooked playing."on verso. "3 cols am" on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - That's how the other accident happened., 1927; 1927.0156.Orr; A man in an auto labeled "Anti-Saloon League interests" is starting to approach a railroad crossing. Rather than stopping for an approaching train labeled "Public Interests" the driver of the auto puts his hand up indicating to the train that it should stop. To the right in the foreground is a tombstone that reads "Here lies the Old Saloon." Around the grave site are the pieces from wrecked autos."overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso. " (Oversize 16)
    - Time for a thorough understanding., no date appears on cartoon - copyright paper overlay torn - placed with 1927 cartoons; 1927.0157.Orr; Cartoon in two scenes: Upper scene shows Uncle Sam playing a game of cards with a man labeled "Rest of the World." The "Rest of the world" has cards tucked in his clothing. The card table is labeled "Honest Naval disarmament." Uncle Sam says, "Shall be play a friendly game ----" In the bottom scene Uncle Sam is shown placing an enormous bag of money labeled "Money enough to out-build the rest of the world" on the table and continues saying, "--or would you like to make it a 'no limit' game?" In the left hand corner are bags of money labeled "U.S. wealth."of preliminary sketch for cartoon on verso. Preliminary sketch for unknown cartoon on verso. Torn paper overlay: ...by The Chicago Tribune" (Oversize 16)
    - The trail of prohibition., 1927; 1927.0158.Orr; The Chicago Tribune. A man with a gun labeled "Hired Killer - protected under prohibition laws" is shown with a trail of "Poisoned citizen" and "Murdered citizen" littering the ground from where he came from. Walking behind the man is the grim reaper holding a bottle of "Poisoned liquor."of preliminary sketch for cartoon on verso. Sketch of a man sitting at a desk, and of a desk also on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - A tough proposition., 1927; 1927.0159.Orr; Mars is leaning his neck over a chopping block labeled "End of War." A man labeled "World," has an axe labeled "Naval disarmament" raised in the air. Scattering the ground are broken axes labeled "Plan to end war,"Pacifism,"Bryan's scheme to end war by treaties,"War prevention,"League of Nations scheme to end war,' "Scheme to end war by alliances," and "Holy alliance." Mars says, "Quit yer ticklin'" cols am" written on recto bottom edge. Preliminary sketches for unknown cartoons on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - There's some real bail under that rock, Mister.", 31 Jul 1927; 1927.0160.Orr; A man labeled "Eastern Politicians" is fishing. In the water a large fish jumps out of the water labeled "Farm vote." In the foreground is a large tackle box labeled "political lures to fool the farmer." To the left is an enormous rock labeled "Removal of farm troubles."doodles for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols Sunday am July 31." written on recto bottom edge. " (Oversize 16)
    - Trying to tow us., 1927; 1927.0161.Orr; A large ship labeled "U.S. Foreign policy" is being towed by "Borah" in a row boat in the direction of "Pacifism."overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - There are lots of chores around the place he could do., 1927; 1927.0162.Orr; A boy in the shape of a bag of money and labeled "American Capital" is headed out fishing in water labeled "Europe." A sign warns of "Danger - deep water." A fish is jumping out of the water labeled "8% interest." In the background by a fence labeled "U.S.A." are various tools scattered around. The tools are labeled "Farm financing,"Flood control,"Waterway development,"Electrification of our railroads,"American investments," and "Reforestation." Uncle Sam is standing behind the fence scratching his head and saying, "I wish I could get that boy interested in stayin' at home."sketches for cartoon on verso. "3 cols am." written on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - There's more than enough to go around, but you have to work for it.", 1927; 1927.0163.Orr; In the upper left corner sits a plump turkey labeled "U.S. Prosperity" on a tree branch. Below sits a boy on a stump labeled "Some of us leisure lovers." The boy says, "Gee! I just love to sit here an' think how good he's gonna be." Behind him is "Old Man opportunity" who holds a large axe next to a grind stone labeled "Hard work." He points to it and says to the boy, "Come on, get busy!"and pumpkins on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Team-work needed., 1927; 1927.0164.Orr; In the foreground a farmer labeled "Mid-west" is trying to pull a stump labeled "Agricultural problems" out of his field with his horse labeled "Midwestern political strength." In the background is a farmer labeled "The South" who is also trying to pull a stump out of the ground. That stump is labeled "Agricultural problem" and the horse doing the work is labeled "Southern political strength." The "Midwest" says to "The South,"Say, Colonel - Maybe if we hitched'em up together we could accomplish something."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Uncle Santa Claus, 1927; 1927.0165.Orr; Uncle Sam is dressed as Santa Claus and sits on a large bag of money labeled "Control of World Finances" on the top of the globe. Going around the circumference of the globe are stockings labeled "Japan, "Russia,"Poland,"Germany,"France,"Italy,"Balkans,"S. America,"C. America," and "Mexico." A sign by the stockings reads "Dear Santy - Please bring us some loans." Uncle Sam is looking through a large book labeled "U.S. Credit book on foreign nations," and says, "Let's see, now - which are the good little boys and which are the bad ones?"sketch for cartoon on verso. "3 cols am" written on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Waiting for a chance to kick the ladder out from under him., 1927; 1927.0166.Orr; Uncle Sam is standing at the top of a ladder picking fruit from a tree that is labeled "World Finance" and "World trade." The ladder is labeled "America's exalted position" and holding the ladder are two men who are labeled "U.S. Navy" and "U.S. Army." They hold a sign that reads, "A weak army and an insufficient Navy protecting our interests." Beneath the tree are men labeled "Foreign powers" who are whispering, shaking their fists and carrying a sign labeled "Jealousy of U.S."sketch for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols am" written on recto bottom edge." (Oversize 16)
    - Waning popularity., 1927; 1927.0167.Orr; Cartoon in two scenes: Upper scene is of the "Dem" Donkey and the "GOP" Elephant racing to carry the bags of a man. The donkey says, "I saw him first!" and the elephant saying, "Carry your bags, Mister?" The man's bags are labeled "Anti-Saloon league support." which is stuffed with votes. The scene is labeled "A few years back." The bottom scene is labeled " --and now." The donkey is saying "Gangway!" and the elephant says "Keep away from me" as they run away from the "AntiSaloon League support." The bags contained a skunk labeled "Scandal."on verso of elephant head. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols. am" on recto bottom edge." (Oversize 16)
    - The wardrobe of the night worker., 1927; 1927.0168.Orr; A man stands in front of his wardrobe looking at two outfits trying to decide what to wear. He says, "Let's see, which suit had I better put on to-night?" The suit to the left is that of the "KKK." A sign to the left reads "List of persons to be flogged." The suit to the right is that of an "Anti-Saloon League." A sign to the right reads "List of homes to be 'snooped.'" cols am" written on recto bottom edge. Portion of preliminary sketch on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Wearing themselves out shooting at him., 1927; 1927.0169.Orr; A knight in armor is labeled "Hoover's invulnerable record" and carries a large shield labeled "H.H." and a flag labeled "G.O.P. standard." He stands on a hill surrounded by arrows that have been unable to harm him. The broken arrows are labeled "Futile attacks." To the left are Native Americans labeled "Hoover Critics." A teepee in the background is labeled "Dem Tribe."doodles on verso. "3 cols Sunday am" on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - We mustn't forget what's back of it., 1927; 1927.0170.Orr; A young boy labeled "This generation" holds up his knife and fork in preparation of eating a large turkey that covers an entire table. The turkey is labeled "Our blessings" and the table is labeled "Thanksgiving." In the background is an apparition of a pilgrim sitting at the table with his head bowed and hands folded. He is labeled "The real spirit of thankfulness for our blessings." cols am" written on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Where is everybody anyway?, 1927; 1927.0171.Orr; Two attractive young women labeled "The nomination sisters" are standing under the "1928 Presidential mistletoe." To the left is a doorway labeled "Backward Democratic leaders" and to the right is a doorway labeled "Shy republican leaders." None of the men are coming the kiss the ladies."paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by ...." Preliminary doodles to unknown drawings on verso. " (Oversize 16)
    - The wind that blows from every direction., 1927; 1927.0172.Orr; Hats are being blown from all directions into a pile. The winds that blow them in are labeled "Presidential hopes." The hats are labeled "Senator, "Mayor, " Governor, "Congress,"Congressman," and "General."sketch for unknown cartoon on verso. Writing with doodle of an airplane. " 3 cols am" written on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Wonder why the rest of the gang doesn't come on in., 1927; 1927.0173.Orr; Uncle Sam has jumped off a diving board into water labeled "Naval Disarmament." On the shore, men labeled "France, Japan and England" are taking Uncle Sam's clothes and tying knots in them and punching a hole through his hat. One man says, "Now let's all hurry up and get dressed before he comes out." A sign on the clothes reads "America's naval ratio."of preliminary doodle for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - The wolf at the door and the bear at the front gate., 1927; 1927.0174.Orr; At a building labeled "Japan" a wolf labeled "Financial Panic" is at the door. At the outside gate labeled "Manchuria" there is a bear labeled "Soviet Russia Menace."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - While the victim drowns., 1927; 1927.0175.Orr; In the foreground is a donkey labeled "Democratic Party" that is drowning." In the background is a dock labeled "Democratic leaders fighting for the honor of saving their party." A rowboat labeled "The nomination" is at the dock. At the boat house labeled "Democratic life saving station," groups of men are fighting which is labeled "Smith-McAdoo feud!"Party dissension!" and "Disorganization!"of preliminary sketch for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - We hope China hasn't been watching us handle Mexico., 1927; 1927.0176.Orr; In the background, Uncle Sam stands behind a fence labeled "U.S.A." He has a rifle in his hand and holds a sign that says, "'U.S. Will protect its Citizens in China' - Sec. Kellog." A man labeled "Mexico" is leaning on the fence to the right and says, "Don't let him blufff you, kid!" A sign reads, "Kellog threatens Mexico, but U.S. Senate votes arbitration." Standing in the foreground is the back of a man labeled "China" who is holding a rifle."sketches for cartoon on verso. Torn paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chic..." (Oversize 16)
    - What we're saving on one star boarder we're losing on the other., 1927; 1927.0177.Orr; At a table labeled "Taxpayer's boarding house" is a thin Uncle Sam and a large man labeled "State Gov'ts" who is eating. The chair Uncle Sam is sitting in is labeled "U.S. Gov't economy." Uncle Sam's meal is being taken by "State Gov'ts" and his meal is labeled "What the Gov't leaves." Other dishes and food on the table is labeled "Taxes," and "Increased Taxes." A dish fallen on the floor is labeled "Waste." A waiter labeled "Taxpayer" brings more trays labeled "More Taxes."State Gov'ts" says to Uncle Sam, I'm sure glad Doc. Coolidge put you on a diet."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - What strange things we're hearing from China nowadays., 1927; 1927.0178.Orr; A lion labeled "Great Britain" is being chased by a small mouse labeled "Chinese Nationalists." Bones are scattered on the ground and labeled "Surrender of British concessions." The mouse says "RRRR-Roar!" and the lion says, "Squeek!" In the background Uncle Sam scratches his head and says, "Old Leo seems to be losing his voice."of preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Waiting to see if they're going to shoot., 1927; 1927.0179.Orr; To the left in the "Black Hills," Coolidge is hiding behind the hill and waving a large hat on a stick. The hat is labeled "Third Term Question. Coolidge is labeled "Lone Scout Cal, lying low and saying nothing." Off in the distance to the far right is a camp of Native Americans. A man is labeled "Chief Borah" and the camp is labeled "Wild tribe of insurgent Republicans."doodles for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Wonder who's underneath it?, 1927; 1927.0180.Orr; A large hand from the upper right corner labeled "Ku Klux Investigation" is pulling the hooded robe off of a man. The robe is labeled "K.K.K. Disguise." The man is labeled "Anti-Saloon." Pieces of paper are falling that read, "Ind. Political scandals,"Dry politics," and "Secret rule of Indiana." His umbrella is labeled "Bigotry."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Where the rivers meet., 1927; 1927.0181.Orr; In the foreground is a woman in water labeled "Mississippi Flood Victims." She is waving for help. In the background are the "Missouri R.,"Mississippi R.,"Illinois R.,"Wabash R.,"Ohio R.," and "Tennessee" waterways that lead into the Mississippi River. Boats are traveling down the waterways labeled "Help from West,"Help from North,"Help from East," and "Help from South."overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Will disarmament end war?, 1927; 1927.0182.Orr; A man labeled "Pacifist" holds a sign that reads "End war by disarmament." In the far distance is "Geneva" with a flag that reads "Naval disarmament." To the left is the enormous figure of "Mars" who is laughing saying, "Some of my best customers are those who are least prepared for war." He holds a sign that reads, "Mexico - China - Balkans." On the ground are weapons with a bloody spear."of preliminary sketch on verso. Other doodles on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - We haven't noticed that he has cut anything down yet., 1927; 1927.0183.Orr; A small boy labeled "Wayne Wheeler" is standing with an axe labeled "Volstead Law" and pointing to a large tree labeled "The Drink Question." There are small cuts in the tree bark and Wheeler says, "I did it with my little hatchet." Uncle Sam is standing to the right and says to the boy, "Aren't you kinda premature in your admission?"sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - Wonder what's going to happen when their bull-dog meets our pet poodle., 1927; 1927.0184.Orr; In the foreground a man labeled "Europe" is feeding his bulldog labeled "Hatred and Distrust of America" a platter of bones labeled "Anti-American propaganda." In the background is a home labeled "U.S." with a man labeled "Our internationalists" feeding milk to his dog labeled "Childish faith in everything European."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - The All-American platform., 1928; 1928.0001.Orr; Uncle Sam holds "The Constitution" in one hand as he holds his other hand down on a tombstone that reads "Here lies the religious issue. Killed by our forefathers in 1787." He is standing on a grave where inside a body calls "Protestant! " WOW!!"GRRR,"Catholic!"Let me out!" A piece of clothing from the grave is labeled "Religious issue."sketch for cartoon on verso. "3 cols am." written on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1928, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 16)
    - The annual reminder., 1927; 1928.0002.Orr; Mars" is standing knocking at the door of "U.S. Income Tax Payer." He holds in his other hand a "Bill for unpreparedness in 1917 - 10th annual payment due March 15, 1928."paper overlay: 1928, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso." (Oversize 16)
    - Another blindfold test., 1928; 1928.0003.Orr; Uncle Sam is sitting in a chair, blindfolded, and smoking testing different brands of cigars. On the floor are cigars that he has tried that are labeled "World Court,"The League,"Naval Treaty," and "Bryan Treaties." In back of Uncle Sam is a man labeled "Our Pacifists" who has put down a box of "Internationalism brand Peace Smokes." Uncle Sam is smoking a cigar labeled "New Peace Treaties" and is starting to choke as he says, "Tastes like the same old brand ----Kau-u-ff!"is signed: Orr - with apologies. Doodles on verso. "3 cols Sunday am" on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1928, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketch for cartoon on the verso of 1928.0044.Orr." (Oversize 16)